articleblotter.com 2018-10-12

# Privacy Policy | Article Blotter

_**Updated**_ ** _ _** _ **March 25, 2016**_

_While you are visiting the Article Blotter website, you may be exposed to other services offered by_ _Article Blotter_ _This policy notice is meant to provide a statement explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used in_ _Article Blotter_ _services including desktop, tablet, mobile devices, and among_ _Article Blotter’s_ _network of affiliated websites which includes any sites or services owned, operated, offered by, or on behalf of—_ _Article Blotter_ _or its affiliates._

## The Information We Collect

Article Blotter, our service providers, advertisers and partners may collect various types of non-personally identifiable information when you visit any of our sites. A representative list of the types of non-personally identifiable information we may collect include: current Internet protocol address and type of browser you are using (e.g., Firefox, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using, (e.g., Microsoft Windows or Mac OS), the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g., Comcast, Verizon or AT&T), the web pages you have visited, sites visited before and after you visit a site on Article Blotter’s Services, the type of handheld or mobile device used to view the site (e.g., iPhone, Blackberry), location information, the content you have accessed and the advertisements you have been shown and/or clicked on. Google Analytics is the primary platform which collects and interprets this data for Article Blotter and Article Blotter services. Article Blotter has made allowances to limit the specificity of the way this information is collected and stored by Google such as anonymizing the IP addresses collected, not sharing data with other parties.

You also can engage with our content, such as video, games, applications, and other offerings, on or through third-party social networking sites, such as Facebook or other social media plug-ins and applications. When you engage with our content on or through third party social networking sites, plug-ins and applications, you may allow us to have access to certain information from your social media profile (e.g., name, e-mail address, photo, gender, birthday, location, your list of friends, people you follow and/or who follow you, the posts or the ‘likes’ you make) to deliver the content or as part of the operation of the application. We may also obtain non-personally identifiable information (e.g., content viewed, game performance, high scores, and information about advertisements within the content you have been shown or may have clicked on,) from your interaction with our content. Any information provided to Article Blotter that may or may not be used by third parties such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+, or others, is not collected by Article Blotter, and if you wish to prevent Article Blotter from collecting such information refer to the privacy policies of those respective services, and make adjustments, if needed, to the type of information you have provided to them for sharing with services and third parties, such as Article Blotter.

The information provided to Article Blotter through Social Media accounts is at you own discretion, but once made available to Article Blotter, information such as your Facebook profile name or picture, Twitter handle, Google+ profile picture and name, or other aspects of readily-available information may be made public on Article Blotter or any of our services offered.

Through some social networking sites’ privacy settings, you can control what data you share. For more information about how social networking sites handle your personal information, please refer to their privacy policies and terms of use.

## How We Use the Information

We may use the information you provide about yourself to fulfill your requests for our products, programs, and services, to respond to your inquiries about our offerings, to offer you other products, programs or services that we believe may be of interest to you, to enforce the legal terms that govern your use of our sites, and/or for the purposes for which you provided the information.

If you choose to submit content for publication (e.g., a letter to our editors, comments sent to our television personalities, a posting to a blog or a discussion board, a video), we may publish your screen name and other information you have provided to us without seeking prior approval.

We may on occasion combine information we collect through our sites with information that we collect from other sources.

We use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our sites, to deliver more relevant marketing messages and advertisements and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information to analyze usage of our sites, as well as to offer you products, programs, or services.

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

Our entire site, not just forums or checkout pages, is secured with a SHA256 SSL Security measure which encrypts data transferred between Article Blotter and yourself. This protects your information from being collected by third parties, or non-acknowledged collection agencies.

We may disclose personally identifiable information in response to legal process, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency’s request, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our terms of use, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our sites and applicable laws or as otherwise required or permitted by law or consistent with legal requirements.

Our agents and contractors who have access to personally identifiable information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this privacy statement and are not authorized to use the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for us.

Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this privacy statement. To insure specific information not be shared with third parties you should not provide, transfer, share, or otherwise make readily available electronic or analogous versions of such information to Article Blotter or its services.

## Cookies & Web Beacons

To enhance your online experience, we use “cookies” or similar technologies. Cookies are text files placed in your computer’s browser to store your preferences. Cookies do not contain personally identifiable information; however, once you choose to furnish a site with personally identifiable information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

We use cookies to understand site and Internet usage and to improve or customize the content, offerings or advertisements on our sites.

We, our third party service providers, advertisers or our partners also may use cookies to manage and measure the performance of advertisements displayed on or delivered by or through the Article Blotter’s Services and/or other networks or sites. This also helps us, our service providers and partners provide more relevant advertising. For more information regarding third-party ad servers, see “Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites, Ad Servers, and Sponsors” below.

We, our third party service providers, advertiser or our partners may also use “web beacons” or clear .gifs, or similar technologies, which are small pieces of code placed on a web page, to monitor the behavior and collect data about the visitors viewing a web page. For example, web beacons may be used to count the users who visit a web page or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a visitor viewing that page.

You can change your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies and similar technologies through your browser. You may set your browser to accept all cookies, block certain cookies, require your consent before a cookie is placed in your browser, or block all cookies. Blocking all cookies will affect your online experience and may prevent you from enjoying the full features offered by Article Blotter’s Services.

## Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites, Ad Servers, and Sponsors

Some of our sites contain links to or integration with other sites such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, etc., whose information practices may be different than ours. Visitors should consult the other sites’ privacy notices as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.

We also use the services of reputable third parties to provide us with data collection, reporting, ad response measurement, and site analytics, as well as to assist with delivery of relevant marketing messages and advertisements. These third parties may view, edit or set their own cookies. We, our third party service providers, advertisers and/or partners may also place web beacons for these third parties. The use of these technologies by these third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this privacy statement.

Some products or services advertised or otherwise recommended on this site may be sponsored by third party affiliates such as ClickBank, Commission Junction, Share a Sale, or other such entities. When you sign up for or purchase any one of these services, you are entering into a contract with those parties, and subsequent information entered such as credit cards numbers, billing addresses, or zip codes are gathered and protected by those third parties. Records of your information may be kept by third parties for various reasons including order fulfillment, advertising, promotional offers, or other purposes. To understand the means in which your information is used by these third parties you need to reference their unique privacy policy and terms of service. While Article Blotter takes every measure to ensure our third party partners or affiliates are of sound operational character, we have no control over their handling of your information.

## Ad Choices

Article Blotter attempts to provide you with ads that are relevant to you. Advertising allows Article Blotter to provide you with the most up-to-date content. Often our ads are based on the content of pages you are viewing, but we also provide ads tailored to your interests. Our hope is that by presenting ads tailored to your interests, we will enhance your experience across Article Blotter Services.

## Our Commitment to Security

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, to maintain data security, and to use correctly the information we collect online. Our use of HTTPS protocols, as well as allowing for anonymous commenting through our Disqus commenting system enhance your ability to communicate securely, and anonymously with Article Blotter services. Access to personally identifiable information that is collected from our sites and that we maintain may be available to you. For example, if you created a password-protected account within our site, you can access that account to review the information you provided.

You may also send an e-mail or letter to the following e-mail or street address requesting access to or correction of your personally identifiable information. For verification purposes please include your first name, last name, e-mail address and the password you use for such service.

_E-mail us at: info@_ _articleblotter.com_

### Updates & Effective Date

_This privacy statement may be updated at any time to accommodate for changes in practice by_ _Article Blotter_ _without notification. We encourage you to periodically check back and review this statement so that you always will know what information we collect, how we use it, and with whom we share it._
